Wayne Starr

racer159@outlook.com

Profile

Fifth Year Software Engineering Student at Rochester Institute of Technology with 4.5 years of leadership experience from Air Force ROTC. Excels at C#, Java, JavaScript, Visual Basic, Python, C++, and C application development; always willing to learn.

Education

Rochester Institute of Technology - 2011-Present (Grad 2016)

Rochester, NY | 3.84 GPA | Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering | Minor in Military Sciences | Immersion in Arabic

Courses: Software Engineering, Engr Fund Comp Systems, Personal Software Engr, Intro To Cs Theory, Operating Systems I, Eng Of Software Subsys, Eng of Concur Distrib SW Sys, Software Testing, Human Centered Reqs and Design, SW Process and Project Management, Engineering of Enterprise SW Sys, Mathematical Models of SW, Intro to Intelligent Systems, SW Process and Product Quality, Principles of Data Mining, SW System Reqs and Architect

Skills

Programming Languages: C#, Java, JavaScript, Ruby, Visual Basic, Python, C++, C, HTML, CSS

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux, Mac OS X

Development Software: Microsoft Visual Studio, Eclipse, Android Studio, Microsoft Visio

Software: Microsoft Office Suite, Microsoft Power BI

Projects

- Worked in free time on a project with a group of interns to explore people's stories through the use of personable "explorers" that prompt for videos, photos, and audio inputs. This project, called <u>Project Atlas</u>, used lights and sounds driven by a windows phone with additional hardware to help the bots "survive" when out in the world.
- Implemented a new interface for class search and enrollment written in Angular.js as part of the Student IT Office, working with external customers around campus as well as the Information Technology Services department.
- Created a Universal Windows Application for watching live internet television called <u>Kiwi TV</u>. This project was launched
 in the <u>Windows Store</u> in April of 2016, and has been in development since.

Experience

Student IT Office, Rochester New York

Web Developer | Jan 2014 - May 2014, Sep 2014 - Dec 2014, Jan 2016 - Present

- Design, Develop, Test, Deploy, and Maintain enterprise-level web apps for RIT
- Work with a cross-functional team to improve business, development, and design processes

Microsoft, Seattle Washington

Software Developer in Test (Intern) | Jun 2014 – Aug 2014, May 2015 – Aug 2015

- Work with Big Data to discover insights to find ways of improving log scraping for Bing
- Create dynamic reports on data using Excel, and SharePoint

Honors/Activities

- RIT Presidential Scholarship recipient
- 4.5 years leadership experience in Air Force Reserve Officer Training Corps
- 3.5 years in Arnold Air Society with 12 months as Area 01 Financial Management Officer
- Placed on Dean's List all academic quarters/semesters
- Enjoy mountain biking, video gaming, snowshoeing, working on cars and off-roading